Finding Aid for Provost and Executive Vice-President for Academic Affairs (University of Michigan) Staff Files
Bentley Historical Library
- Monts, Lester P., 1974-2009; 41.85 linear feet
  Records from Monts in the Staff Files were accessioned as part of other Provost's Office transfers. The majority of the records were created after his appointment as Associate Provost in 1998, with a few exceptions. Researchers using the Monts files may also want to consult the Vice President for Academic and Multicultural Affairs (VPAMA) records collection, which contains documentation on Monts' service in this position as well as some records as Associate Provost which overlap with materials found in the Provost's Office Staff Files. The series measures 43 linear feet.
  Lester Monts files consist of seven series: Office of the Associate Provost Files, General Files, Unit Files, Budget Files, Chronological Files, Committees, and Awards. The arrangement reflects the original organization of the records when accessioned. While there are some records from Monts' service as Vice Provost, the bulk of the records date after 1998, when he became Associate Provost.
  - Office of the Associate Provost files
    - Academic Services Board
      The Office of the Associate Provost Files is a small series of records maintained mainly by Pamela Horne. They include materials from Academic Service Board (ASB) meetings and information on a conference on African music and dance.
      - 1974-1989, 2 folders (Box 505)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 505)
      - 1990-1993, 2 folders (Box 505)
      - Retention Subcommittee (Box 505)
    - Conference on Music and Dance of Africa
      - Abstracts, 1997 (Box 505)
      - Budget and Finances, 1996-1997 (Box 505)
      - Concert Publicity, 1997 (Box 505)
      - Conference Roster, 1997 (Box 505)
      - Planning Committee and Staff Notes, 1997 (Box 505)
      - Program, 1997 (Box 505)
      - Registration and Publicity, 1997 (Box 505)
      - Speakers and Workshops, 1997 (Box 505)
  - General Files
    - Pre-1998
      - Academic Calendar (Box 506)
        - 1991-1994 (Box 506)
        - 1993-1994 (Box 506)
        - 1992-1997 (Box 506)
        - 1997-1998 (Box 506)
      - Admissions Lawsuit, 1997 (Box 549)
      - Africa, Music and Dance of, 1997 (Box 506)
      - African Music and Dance, Center for, 1994-2000 (Box 506)
      - Campus Diversity Initiatives: Practices in Diversity, 1997 (Box 506)
      - Computing, 1995-1997 (Box 506)
      - Diversity Ad Hoc Committee (Box 506)
      - Equity within the Classroom, 1998 (Box 506)
      - Financial Aid Fiscal Planning Group (FAFPG), 1997-1998 (Box 506)
      - Hardwick Grievance, 1996-1997 (Box 506)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of -- Internal/External Reviews, 1997-1998 (Box 506)
      - Medical Excuse Policy, 1998 (Box 506)
      - Office of Academic and Multicultural Initiatives (OAMI) -- Martin Luther King Symposium, 1994 (Box 506)
      - Office of the Associate Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs
        - General, 1997 (Box 506)
        - SAB and Tom Group Meetings, 1997 (Box 506)
      - Patterson Institute, 1997-1998 (Box 506)
      - Personal Research, ca. 1990-1994 (Box 506)
      - Personnel
        - Davis, Jacina, 1996 (Box 506)
      - Post-Doctoral Fellowship, 1997-1998 (Box 506)
      - Presentations, 1996 (Box 506)
      - President's Initiatives on Women, 1997-1998 (Box 506)
      - Race Coding, 1995-1999 (Box 506)
      - Residency Appeal Committee
        - General, 1997-1998 (Box 506)
        - General Counsel, 1996-1998 (Box 549)
          [Patient/client records restricted until July 01, 2098 ]
      - Textbook Issue, 1995-1998 (Box 506)
      - University of Michigan Party at Business Administration Building Photographs, 1994 (Box 549)
      - Washtenaw Alliance for Minority Scholars (MET)
        - 1993-1995 (Box 506)
        - 1994-2001 (Box 549)
      - Women of Color in the Academy, 1994; 1998 (Box 506)
      - Women's Agenda, 1996-1997 (Box 506)
    - 1998/1999
      - Academic Affairs Directors (Box 506)
      - Academic Calendar (Box 506)
      - Admissions Lawsuit, 2 folders (Box 506)
      - American Culture (Box 506)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) Fellows
        - Gillum, Linda (Box 506)
      - Bahamas Baptist Community College (Box 506)
      - Carnegie PEW Scholars (Box 506)
      - Center for Learning through Community Service -- Faculty Council (Box 506)
      - Department of Public Safety (DPS) Search (Box 506)
      - Distance Learning Edgar Beckham Visits (Box 506)
      - Evaluations and Examinations (Box 506)
      - Faculty Promotions (Box 506)
      - Financial Aid Fiscal Planning Group (FAFPG) (Box 506)
      - Honors on the University Transcript (Box 507)
      - International Institute
        - Center for Russian and Eastern European Studies (CREES) Review (Box 507)
        - Executive Board (Box 507)
      - MPathways (Box 507)
      - Office of New Student Programs
        - General (Box 507)
        - Personnel (Box 507)
      - Personnel
        - Gohsman, John L. (Box 507)
      - Religious Issues (Box 507)
      - Universitas 21 (Box 507)
    - 1999/2000
      - Academic Calendar (Box 507)
      - Academic Program Group (APG) (Box 507)
      - Academic Services Board (ASB) (Box 507)
      - Accreditation (Box 507)
      - Admissions Lawsuits (Box 507)
      - Admissions -- Other Universities (Box 507)
      - Affirmative Action -- Reports, Articles (Box 507)
      - African American Students (Box 507)
      - African Music (Box 507)
      - African Music Symposium (Box 507)
      - Alumni Association of UM (Box 507)
      - American Association of Higher Education (AAHE) (Box 507)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) Fellows Program (Box 507)
      - American Culture (Box 507)
      - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 507)
      - Architecture and Urban Planning (Box 507)
      - Articles, General (Box 507)
      - Art, School of (Box 507)
      - Arts Advisory Board (Box 507)
      - Arts at Michigan Office (Box 507)
      - Association of American Colleges and Universities (AACU) (Box 507)
      - Athlete Students (Box 549)
        [Student records restricted until July 01, 2085 ]
      - Bahamas Baptist Community College (Box 549)
      - Bentley Foundation (Box 507)
      - Black Student Union (Box 507)
      - Business Administration, School of (Box 507)
      - Carnegie Foundation (Box 507)
      - Center for Afroamerican Studies (Box 507)
      - Center for Equal Opportunity (CEO) Reports (Box 507)
      - Center for Learning through Community Service (Box 507)
      - Chemistry (Box 549)
      - Chief Financial Officer (CFO) (Box 507)
      - Citi-Assist (Box 507)
      - College Board (Box 507)
      - College Rankings (Box 507)
      - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC) (Box 507)
      - Comprehensive Studies Program (CSP) (Box 507)
      - Conferences (Box 507)
      - Correspondence (Box 507)
      - Deans Orientation -- New (Box 507)
      - Dentistry, School of (Box 549)
      - Development at U of M (Box 507)
      - Eastern Michigan University (EMU) College of Education Board (Box 507)
      - Education, Department of (Box 507)
      - Education, School of (Box 508)
        - General (Box 508)
        - Nettles, Michael (Box 508)
        - Personnel (Box 508)
      - Engineering, College of
        - General (Box 508)
        - Minority Engineering Programs Office (MEPO)/Summer Engineering Academy (SEA) Incident (Box 549)
      - Enrollment Working Group (EWG) (Box 508)
      - Equity within the Classroom (Box 508)
      - Faculty of Color (Box 508)
      - Financial Aid
        - General (Box 508)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - Foundations (Box 508)
      - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 1997-2000 (Box 508)
      - General Counsel
        - General (Box 508)
        - Gratz v. Bollinger (Box 549)
      - Government Relations, Vice President (Box 508)
      - Gullah Symposium (Box 508)
      - Health Sciences (Box 508)
      - High Hopes for America's Youth (Box 508)
      - Hindu Student Council (Box 508)
      - Hispanic (Box 508)
      - Honorary Degrees (Box 508)
      - Honors Program (Box 508)
      - Housing (Box 508)
      - Human Resources and Affirmative Action (HRAA) (Box 508)
      - Information Technology Division (ITD) (Box 508)
      - International Institute
        - General (Box 508)
        - Executive Board (Box 508)
      - International Programs, Office of
        - General (Box 508)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - Israel Trip (Box 508)
      - K-12 Programs (Box 508)
      - Kellogg Foundation (Box 508)
      - Kinesiology, Division of (Box 508)
      - Labor Studies Center (Box 508)
      - Law School (Box 508)
      - Leadershape (Box 508)
      - Lesbian Gay Bisexual Faculty Alliance (Box 508)
      - Library Science, School of (Box 508)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of (Box 508)
      - Living Learning Communities (Box 508)
      - Marketing Communications (Box 508)
      - Martin Luther King (MLK) Symposium (Box 508)
      - Media Union (Box 508)
      - Medical School (Box 508)
      - Michigamua Issue (Box 508)
      - Michigan Leadership (Box 508)
      - Michigan Union (Box 508)
      - Minority Engineering Program Office (MEPO) (Box 508)
      - MPathways (Box 508)
      - MPathways Racial Coding (Box 508)
      - M-TIES Program (Box 508)
      - Music, School of (Box 508)
      - Muslim Students (Box 508)
      - National Alliance for Excellence (Box 508)
      - New Dean Orientation (Box 508)
      - North Central Accreditation, 1997-2000 (Box 508)
      - Nursing, School of (Box 508)
      - Office of Academic and Multicultural Initiatives (OAMI) (Box 509)
        - General (Box 509)
        - Budget (Box 509)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - Office of New Student Programs
        - General (Box 509)
        - Budget (Box 509)
      - Open Position Reply (Pam's Position) (Box 509)
      - Office of New Student Programs (Box 509)
      - Pathways to Student Success and Excellence (POSSE) (Box 509)
      - Patterson Institute (Box 509)
      - Pharmacy, College of (Box 509)
      - Pierpont Commons Strategic Plans (Box 509)
      - Pierpont Renovation Committee (Box 509)
      - President's Advisory (Box 509)
      - President's Office (Box 509)
      - Proposal (Box 509)
      - Public Goods Council (Box 509)
      - Public Health, School of (Box 509)
      - Rackham, School
        - General (Box 509)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - Recruitment and Scholarship Committee (Box 509)
      - Registrar, Office of
        - General (Box 509)
        - Budget (Box 509)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - Research (Box 509)
      - Residency (Box 509)
      - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA) (Box 509)
      - Sociology, Department of -- Grievance (Box 509)
      - South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) (Box 509)
      - Speaker Initiatives (Box 509)
      - State of Michigan (Box 509)
      - Stearns Collection (Box 509)
      - Student Affairs, Vice President for
        - General (Box 509)
        - Search (Box 509)
      - Student Issues (Box 549)
      - Undergraduate Commission (Box 509)
      - University College Partnership -- Rackham (Box 509)
      - University Musical Society (UMS), 2 folders (Box 509)
      - Valez-Aguayo, Evelyn (Box 509)
      - Visitors (Box 509)
      - Women of Color (Box 509)
      - World Performance Studies (Box 509)
      - Y2K Emergency Team (Box 509)
    - 2000/2001
      - Academic Affairs
        - General (Box 509)
        - Flexible Funds (Box 509)
        - Office of Academic Affairs (OAA) 5+1 (Box 509)
        - Office of Academic Affairs (OAA) 8+1 (Box 509)
      - Academic Calendar (Box 509)
      - Academic Program Group (APG) (Box 509)
      - Academic Services Board (ASB) (Box 509)
      - Affirmative Action (Box 509)
      - African American Alumni (Box 509)
      - African American Administrators Dinners, 1999-2001 (Box 509)
      - African American Students (Box 509)
      - Alexander, Keith (Box 509)
      - Allen, Elizabeth/ Department of Safety Oversight Committee (Box 510)
      - Alumni Association of UM (Box 510)
      - American Association of Higher Education (AAHE) (Box 510)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 510)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) Fellows Program (Box 510)
      - American Culture, program in (Box 510)
      - Ann Arbor Summer Festival (Box 510)
      - Architecture and Urban Planning, College of (Box 510)
      - Articles (Box 510)
      - Art, School of (Box 510)
      - Arts of Citizenship (Box 510)
      - Arts at Michigan (Box 510)
      - Associate Provost and Associate Deans Group (APADG) (Box 510)
      - Associate Provost Correspondence (Box 510)
      - Associate Provost and Provost Staff Meetings (Box 510)
      - Association of American Colleges and Universities (AACU)
        - General (Box 510)
        - Greater Expectations (Box 510)
      - Association of American Universities (Box 510)
      - Association of Black Professionals, Administrators, Faculty and Staff (ABFAFS) (Box 510)
      - Athletics
        - General (Box 510)
        - Athlete Students (Box 510)
        - Early Registration, 1998-2001 (Box 510)
        - Student Grievance (Box 549)
          [Student records restricted until July 01, 2086 ]
      - Beckham, E. -- Visit to U of M (Box 510)
      - Bell, Betty (Box 549)
      - Binge Drinking Committee (Box 510)
      - Business Administration, School of (Box 510)
      - Center for African and African-American Studies (CAAS) (Box 510)
      - Center for the Education of Women (CEW) (Box 510)
      - Chung, Yoojin (Box 510)
      - Civil Liberties Board, UM (Box 510)
      - College Board (Box 510)
      - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC)
        - General (Box 510)
        - Conference on Best Practice for Diversity (Box 510)
        - Common Market (CIC/CMCI) (Box 510)
        - Diversity Statement (Box 510)
      - Conduct Committee (Box 510)
      - Correspondence (Box 510)
      - Deloria, Vine (Box 510)
      - Dentistry, School of (Box 510)
      - Detroit Public Schools (Box 510)
      - Diverse Democracy (Box 510)
      - Diversity (Box 510)
      - Education, Department of (Box 510)
      - Education, School of (Box 510)
      - Education for Democracy, Center for (Box 510)
      - Embark.com (Box 510)
      - Engineering, College of (Box 510)
      - Enrollment Working Group (EWG) (Box 510)
      - Evaluations and Examinations, Office of (Box 510)
      - Events Office (Box 510)
      - Faculty (Box 510)
      - Financial Aid
        - General (Box 510)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - First Year Experience Report (Box 510)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 510)
      - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) (Box 510)
      - Garcia, Ann (Box 511)
      - General Counsel (Box 511)
        (includes information on Affirmative Action at other institutions)
      - Ginsberg Center for Learning through Community Service, 2 folders (Box 511)
      - Globalizing the Academy (Box 511)
      - Graduate Student Instructors (GSIs) (Box 511)
      - Health Sciences (Box 511)
      - Hispanic Association of Colleges and Universities (HACU) (Box 511)
      - Honors Convocation (Box 511)
      - Honors Council
        - General (Box 511)
        - Rhodes, Marshall, Mitchell Subcommittee (Box 549)
      - Honors Program (Box 549)
      - Human Resources and Affirmative Action (HRAA) (Box 511)
      - Imagining America (Box 511)
      - Institute for Research on Women and Gender (Box 511)
      - International Cultural Series (Box 511)
      - International Institute
        - General (Box 511)
        - Secretariat (Box 511)
      - Labor Studies Center (Box 511)
      - Law School (Box 511)
      - Library Sciences, School of (Box 511)
      - Life Sciences (Box 511)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of (Box 511)
      - Living Learning Communities (Box 511)
      - Martin Luther King (MLK) (Box 549)
      - Medical School
        - General (Box 511)
        - Assistant Dean of Minority Affairs Search (Box 511)
        - Diversity (Box 511)
      - Michigan Administrative Information Services (MAIS) (Box 511)
      - Michigan Community Colleges Association (Box 511)
      - Michigan Student Assembly (MSA) (Box 511)
      - Midwest Consortium for Latino Research (Box 511)
      - MPathways, 3 folders (Box 511)
      - MPathways/Student Administration, 2 folders (Box 511)
      - M-Ties (Box 511)
      - Museums (Box 511)
      - Music, School of
        - General (Box 511)
        - Students (Box 549)
      - Native American Tuition Waiver (Box 511)
      - Office of Academic Affairs/Office of the Vice President for Research/Rackham (OAA/OVPR/Rackham) (Box 511)
      - Office of Academic and Multicultural Initiatives (OAMI) (Box 511)
      - Office of New Student Programs (ONSP) (Box 512)
        - General (Box 512)
        - Student Incident (Box 549)
      - Pathways to Student Success and Excellence (POSSE) Program (Box 512)
      - PMLT -- Pathways, 3 folders (Box 512)
      - President, Office of (Box 512)
      - Proposals (Box 512)
      - Public Goods Council (Box 512)
      - Public Health, School of (Box 512)
      - Racial Issues (Box 512)
      - Rackham, School of (Box 512)
      - Recruiting and Scholarship Committee, 2 folders (Box 512)
      - Regents (Box 512)
      - Registrar, Office of the
        - General (Box 512)
        - Search (Box 512)
        - Student grievance (Box 549)
      - Residency Appeals Committee (Box 549)
      - Residency Issue (Box 549)
      - Rogel Scholarships (Box 512)
      - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA) (Box 512)
      - Social Work, School of (Box 512)
      - South African Initiatives Office (SAIO) (Box 512)
      - State of Michigan (Box 512)
      - Stein, Louise (Box 512)
        [Personnel records restricted until July 01, 2076 ]
      - Student Affairs, Vice President for
        - General (Box 512)
        - Budget (Box 512)
      - Student Issues (Box 512)
      - Students of Color Coalition (SCC)
        - General (Box 512)
        - Background (Box 512)
        - Final Response (Box 512)
      - Summer Institute (Box 512)
      - Textbook Policy (Box 512)
      - Undergraduate Commission (Box 512)
      - Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program (UROP) (Box 512)
      - United Negro College Fund (UNCF) (Box 512)
      - University-Community Partnerships (Box 512)
      - University Musical Society (UMS) (Box 512)
      - University Preparatory Academy (Box 512)
      - Washtenaw AllianceMETA Scholarship Recipients (Box 549)
      - Women of Color (Box 512)
    - 2001/2002
      - Academic Affairs
        - Associate Provost's Meetings (Box 513)
        - Associate Provost's Miscellaneous (Box 513)
        - Provost/Lester Monts (LPM) Meetings (Box 513)
        - Provost's Staff (Box 513)
        - State Budget (Box 513)
      - Academic Calendar (includes Fall Break) (Box 513)
      - Academic Integrity Issue (Box 513)
      - Academic Program Group (Box 513)
      - Admissions -- Other Universities (Box 513)
      - Admissions Systems Production Group (ASP) (Box 513)
      - Affirmative Action Reports (Box 513)
      - Africa/African Miscellaneous (Box 513)
      - Africa Exchange -- Membership (Box 513)
      - African American Music Collection and Standifer Video Archive, 2 folders (Box 513)
      - Alumni Association of UM (Box 513)
      - American Association of Higher Education (AAHE)
        - General (Box 513)
        - Assessment Conference, undated (Box 513)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 513)
      - Amistad (Box 513)
      - Articles (Box 513)
      - Arts at Michigan
        - General (Box 513)
        - Posting (Box 513)
      - Arts of Citizenship (Box 513)
      - Art, School of (Box 513)
      - Associate Provosts and Associate Deans Group (APADG) (Box 513)
      - Association of American Colleges and Universities (AACU)
        - General (Box 513)
        - Greater Expectations Meeting (Box 513)
      - Black Celebratory (Box 513)
      - Business Administration, School of (Box 513)
      - Carnegie Foundation (Box 513)
      - Celebración Latina (Box 513)
      - Center for African and African-American Studies (CAAS) (Box 513)
      - Center for the Education of Women (CEW) (Box 513)
      - China Exchange (Box 513)
      - Coca-Cola Foundation (Box 513)
      - College Board (Box 513)
      - Commercial Advertising (Box 513)
      - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC)
        - General (Box 513)
        - Common Market of Courses Group (Box 513)
      - Computing Evaluation (Box 513)
      - Copyright Policy (Box 513)
      - Correspondence (Box 513)
      - Curricular Practical Training (Box 513)
      - Dentistry, School of
        - General (Box 513)
        - Multicultural Audit, 2 folders (Box 513)
      - Development (Box 513)
      - Diverse Democracy (Box 513)
      - Diversity (Box 513)
      - Education, Department of (Box 513)
      - Education for a Diverse Democracy, Provost's Committee (Box 513)
      - Education, School of (Box 514)
      - EMERGE (Box 514)
      - Engineering, College of (Box 514)
      - Enrollment (Box 514)
      - Enrollment Working Group (EWG) (Box 514)
      - Environmental Justice Initiative (Box 514)
      - European-American Center for International Education (Box 514)
      - Evaluation and Examinations (Box 514)
      - Evans, Billy Joe (Box 549)
        [Patient/client records restricted until July 01, 2102 ]
      - Events Office (Box 514)
      - Executive Officers Meetings (Box 514)
      - External Relations Group (Box 514)
      - Faculty Arts and Humanities Dialogue Group (Box 514)
      - Faculty Data (Box 514)
      - Faculty Promotions (Box 514)
      - Financial Aid
        - General (Box 514)
        - Michigan Indian Tuition Waiver (Box 549)
          [Student records restricted until July 01, 2087 ]
      - Ford Foundation (Box 514)
      - Fowler Museum (Box 514)
      - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) (Box 514)
      - Gates Scholar (Box 514)
      - General Counsel (Box 514)
      - Ginsberg Center for Learning through Community Service (Box 514)
      - Global Intercultural Experience for Undergraduates (GIEU), 2 folders (Box 514)
      - Graduate Student Instructors (GSIs)
        - General (Box 514)
        - Housing (Box 549)
      - Harvard University -- Admissions
        - General (Box 514)
        - Bial Project Student Data (Box 549)
      - Health Sciences Search (Box 514)
      - Hispanic Association of Colleges and Universities (HACU) (Box 514)
      - Honors Convocation (Box 514)
      - Honors Council, 2 folders (Box 514)
      - Honors Program
        - General (Box 514)
        - Angell Scholars (Box 514)
      - Housing (Box 514)
      - Housing Officers Association (Box 514)
      - Human Resources and Affirmative Action (HRAA) (Box 514)
      - Imagining America (Box 514)
      - Indiana University (Box 514)
      - International Institute
        - General (Box 514)
        - Review Report (Box 514)
        - Secretariat (Box 514)
      - Japanese Studies (Box 514)
      - K-12 Educational Outreach (Box 514)
      - Kellogg Foundation (Box 514)
      - LAN Proposal (Box 514)
      - Law School (Box 514)
      - Learning Communities, 1999-2002; 2 folders (Box 514)
      - Libraries (Box 514)
      - Life Sciences (Box 514)
      - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of (Box 515)
      - Living Learning Communities (Box 515)
      - LUCY Initiative (Box 515)
      - Mandate Encouraging Transfer Agreement (META) (Box 515)
      - Martin Luther King (MLK) Symposium (Box 515)
      - Math and Science Scholars Program (MSSP) (Box 515)
      - Medical School (Box 515)